[
  {
    "id": "1",
    "question": "EC50",
    "answer": "Efficacy-Concentration 50: drug concentration that produces 50% of its maximum effect.",
    "links": ["10", "14", "16"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "2",
    "question": "Clearance (CL)",
    "answer": "Drug elimination efficiency: the efficiency of the body at irreversibly removing the drug from blood plasma.<ul><li>Definition: $CL=Q \\frac{C_A-C_V}{C_A} = Q*E$</li><li>Different types: Renal, Hepatic, Others (often negligible)</li><li>We generally say: $CL = CL_R + CL_H$</li></ul>",
    "links": ["13", "84", "86", "87", "88", "94"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "3",
    "question": "Volume of Distribution (Vd)",
    "answer": "Total amount of drug in the body divided by the concentration in the bloodstream. <ul><li>High Vd suggests the drug is distributed widely throughout the body.</li><li>Lower Vd indicates the drug is mostly confined to the blood plasma</li><li>$V_d = V_P + \\frac{f_u * V_T}{f_{ut}}$ (but $V_P$ negligible if $V_d > 40$ L)</li></ul>",
    "links": ["13", "92"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "4",
    "question": "Common Development Endpoints",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Overall survival of patients (traditional endpoint)</li><li>Progression free survival: time patient lives with disease without it worsening</li><li>Durable complete response: complete disappearance of all cancer</li><li>Palliation: reduction in tumor symptoms</li></ul>",
    "links": ["8", "78"],
    "subtopic": "Drug Development"
  },
  {
    "id": "5",
    "question": "LD50",
    "answer": "Lethal Dose 50: dosage of the drug where 50% do not survive.",
    "links": ["16"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "6",
    "question": "CFR",
    "answer": "Code of Federal Regulations. <ul><li>All FDA guidelines and policies are codified in CFR Title 21</li></ul>",
    "links": ["8", "16", "17", "31"],
    "subtopic": "Drug Development"
  },
  {
    "id": "7",
    "question": "DDI Studies",
    "answer": "Drug-drug Interaction Studies: what happens taking other drugs w/ this new drug? <ul><li>Context: Post-Marketing Studies</li></ul>",
    "links": ["8", "29"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "8",
    "question": "Drug Development",
    "answer": "<ol><li>Preclinical (IND)</li><li>Phase 1 (toxicity)</li><li>Phase 2 (efficacy)</li><li>Phase 3 (endpoints)</li><li>FDA Approval (NDA)</li><li>Post-Marketing Studies (EHR)</li></ol>",
    "links": ["4", "6", "7", "16", "17", "51", "56"],
    "subtopic": "Drug Development"
  },
  {
    "id": "9",
    "question": "ADME",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Absorption</li><li>Distribution</li><li>Metabolism</li><li>Excretion</li></ul>",
    "links": ["11", "13"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "10",
    "question": "Potency",
    "answer": "The amount of drug needed to produce a specific effect. It's a measure of the drug's power.",
    "links": ["1", "14", "51"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "11",
    "question": "Preferred Administration Methods",
    "answer": "<ol><li>Oral</li><li>IV</li></ol>",
    "links": ["9"],
    "subtopic": "Drug Development"
  },
  {
    "id": "12",
    "question": "Therapeutic Window",
    "answer": "The concentration between efficacy (low end) and toxicity (high end) on a concentration vs time graph. <ul><li>Small therapeutic windows require more careful dosing</li></ul>",
    "links": ["14"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "13",
    "question": "PK",
    "answer": "Pharmacokinetics: what the body does to the drug.",
    "links": ["2", "3", "9", "14", "15", "18", "20", "32"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "14",
    "question": "PD",
    "answer": "Pharmacodynamics: what the drug does to the body.",
    "links": ["1", "10", "12", "13", "19"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "15",
    "question": "Cmax",
    "answer": "Maximum concentration.",
    "links": ["13", "85"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "16",
    "question": "IND",
    "answer": "Investigational New Drug. <ul><li>Required to begin clinical trials</li><li>Submitted after pre-clinical phase</li></ul>",
    "links": ["1", "5", "6", "8"],
    "subtopic": "Drug Development"
  },
  {
    "id": "17",
    "question": "NDA",
    "answer": "New Drug Application. <ul><li>Required for FDA approval</li><li>Submitted after Phase III</li></ul>",
    "links": ["6", "8"],
    "subtopic": "Drug Development"
  },
  {
    "id": "18",
    "question": "Tmax",
    "answer": "Maximum time.",
    "links": ["13"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "19",
    "question": "Emax",
    "answer": "Maximum Efficacy. <ul><li>Example forms of measurement: reduction in tumor size %</li></ul>",
    "links": ["14"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "20",
    "question": "Half Life",
    "answer": "The time it takes for the drug concentration to decrease to half of its initial amount in the body.<ul><li>$t_{1/2} = \\frac{\\ln(2)*V_d}{CL}$</li></ul>",
    "links": ["13"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "21",
    "question": "VM",
    "answer": "Virtual Machine: a technology that can be used to create isolated computing environments, which can be beneficial for some HPC tasks.",
    "links": ["27"],
    "subtopic": "Computing"
  },
  {
    "id": "22",
    "question": "HPC",
    "answer": "High Performance Computing: focused on achieving high performance through parallel processing, often using specialized in-house hardware and infrastructure.",
    "links": ["26", "27"],
    "subtopic": "Computing"
  },
  {
    "id": "23",
    "question": "Cloud Computing",
    "answer": "The practice of using a network of remote servers hosted on the internet to store, manage, and process data, rather than a local server or a personal computer.",
    "links": ["26", "27"],
    "subtopic": "Computing"
  },
  {
    "id": "24",
    "question": "PHI",
    "answer": "Protected Health Information: inherently identifiable information that requires an IRB.",
    "links": ["29", "31"],
    "subtopic": "Data"
  },
  {
    "id": "25",
    "question": "DeID OMOP",
    "answer": "Observational Medical Outcomes Partnership: global, open-source community data standard designed to standardize the structure and content of observational data and to enable efficient analyses that can produce reliable evidence.",
    "links": ["30"],
    "subtopic": "Data"
  },
  {
    "id": "26",
    "question": "AWS",
    "answer": "Amazon Web Services: cloud-based HPC platform (cloud computing).",
    "links": ["22", "23"],
    "subtopic": "Computing"
  },
  {
    "id": "27",
    "question": "IC",
    "answer": "Information Commons: a physical or virtual space designed to provide integrated access to information resources, technology, and support services, often within an academic library or educational setting. <ul><li>Includes: data (via CDW), computation, tools, and community</li></ul>",
    "links": ["21", "22", "23", "70"],
    "subtopic": "Computing"
  },
  {
    "id": "28",
    "question": "Clinical Concepts",
    "answer": "Extraction of all concepts in clinical notes into structured “clinical concepts”. <ul><li>Example extractions: dosage, ontologies, etc</li></ul>",
    "links": ["69", "70"],
    "subtopic": "Data"
  },
  {
    "id": "29",
    "question": "EHR",
    "answer": "Electronic Health Records. <ul><li>Structured data</li></ul>",
    "links": ["7", "24", "30", "40", "70"],
    "subtopic": "Data"
  },
  {
    "id": "30",
    "question": "DeID",
    "answer": "De-identified Information: names, images, birthdays, etc are all altered or removed for anonymity.",
    "links": ["25", "29"],
    "subtopic": "Data"
  },
  {
    "id": "31",
    "question": "IRB",
    "answer": "Institutional Review Board: a committee that reviews and approves research involving human subjects to ensure ethical and safe practices.",
    "links": ["6", "24"],
    "subtopic": "Drug Development"
  },
  {
    "id": "32",
    "question": "AUC",
    "answer": "Area Under the Curve: measures the area under the ROC curve (ML) or plasma concentration-time curve (PK). <ul><li>1.0 score indicates perfect performance</li><li>0.5 score is random guessing</li><li>In PK: $\\text{AUC} = \\frac{\\text{Dose}}{CL}$</li></ul>",
    "links": ["13", "33", "47", "83"],
    "subtopic": "Metrics"
  },
  {
    "id": "33",
    "question": "ROC Curve",
    "answer": "Used to evaluate the performance of a binary classifier by plotting TPR (y) vs. FPR (x) at various classification thresholds (ex. return True if >0.9 vs just >0.5). <ul><li>The model is classifying well if TPR is high and FPR is low in general</li><li>At a low enough threshold, TPR and FPR will be 100%</li><li>It represents the trade-off between the sensitivity and specificity of a classifier</li></ul>",
    "links": ["32", "34", "35", "36", "37"],
    "subtopic": "Metrics"
  },
  {
    "id": "34",
    "question": "TPR",
    "answer": "True Positive Rate: of all actual positives, how many caught? <ul><li>Also known as Sensitivity or Recall</li></ul>",
    "links": ["33", "36", "38"],
    "subtopic": "Metrics"
  },
  {
    "id": "35",
    "question": "FPR",
    "answer": "False Positive Rate: of all actual negatives, how many missed? <ul><li>$FPR = \\frac{FP}{FP + TN}$</li></ul>",
    "links": ["33"],
    "subtopic": "Metrics"
  },
  {
    "id": "36",
    "question": "Sensitivity",
    "answer": "Of all actual positives, how many caught? <ul><li>Also known as TPR or Recall</li></ul>",
    "links": ["33", "34", "38"],
    "subtopic": "Metrics"
  },
  {
    "id": "37",
    "question": "Specificity",
    "answer": "Of all actual negatives, how many caught? <ul><li>Goal: avoid false positives (like precision, but different strategy)</li><li>Calculated as $1 - FPR = \\frac{TN}{TN + FP}$</li></ul>",
    "links": ["33"],
    "subtopic": "Metrics"
  },
  {
    "id": "38",
    "question": "Recall",
    "answer": "Of all actual positives, how many caught? <ul><li>Goal: Don’t miss any true cases (high recall = few false negatives)</li><li>$\\frac{TP}{TP + FN}$</li></ul>",
    "links": ["34", "36", "47"],
    "subtopic": "Metrics"
  },
  {
    "id": "39",
    "question": "Precision",
    "answer": "Of all positive reports, how many correct? <ul><li>Goal: Don’t make false claims (high precision = few false positives)</li><li>$\\frac{TP}{TP + FP}$</li></ul>",
    "links": ["47"],
    "subtopic": "Metrics"
  },
  {
    "id": "40",
    "question": "Supervised Learning",
    "answer": "Give the model a starting point and end point (labeled data) and the algorithm infers the rules. <ul><li>Utilizes labeled data</li></ul>",
    "links": ["29", "42", "44", "46", "47"],
    "subtopic": "Statistics"
  },
  {
    "id": "41",
    "question": "Unsupervised Learning",
    "answer": "Without labels, model finds hidden patterns on its own. During evaluation, you need to have a strong understanding of what you are looking for (since there is no labeled data)<ul><li>Utilizes unlabeled data</li></ul>",
    "links": ["42", "43"],
    "subtopic": "Statistics"
  },
  {
    "id": "42",
    "question": "Semi-supervised Learning",
    "answer": "Leverage unlabeled data to improve models trained on limited labeled data. <ul><li>Learning from limited labels</li></ul>",
    "links": ["40", "41"],
    "subtopic": "Statistics"
  },
  {
    "id": "43",
    "question": "Dimensionality Reduction",
    "answer": "Goal: reduce number of input variables while preserving as much meaningful structure or variance as possible in order to: <ul><li>simplify model</li><li>improve performance</li><li>reduce overfitting</li></ul>",
    "links": ["41", "48", "49", "50"],
    "subtopic": "Statistics"
  },
  {
    "id": "44",
    "question": "Feature Importance",
    "answer": "Transform raw data into meaningful 'features' (numerical representations) via vectorization.",
    "links": ["40"],
    "subtopic": "Statistics"
  },
  {
    "id": "45",
    "question": "Accuracy",
    "answer": "$\\frac{TP + TN}{TP + FP + TN + FN}$",
    "links": ["47"],
    "subtopic": "Metrics"
  },
  {
    "id": "46",
    "question": "Regression",
    "answer": "Predict continuous numerical value.",
    "links": ["40", "62", "63", "64", "65", "67"],
    "subtopic": "Statistics"
  },
  {
    "id": "47",
    "question": "Classification",
    "answer": "Predict a category or class.",
    "links": ["32", "38", "39", "40", "45", "66", "68"],
    "subtopic": "Statistics"
  },
  {
    "id": "48",
    "question": "PCA",
    "answer": "Dimensionality Reduction Technique: linear, fast, interpretable.",
    "links": ["43"],
    "subtopic": "Statistics"
  },
  {
    "id": "49",
    "question": "UMAP",
    "answer": "Dimensionality Reduction Technique: nonlinear, preserves local and global structure. Great for visualization.",
    "links": ["43"],
    "subtopic": "Statistics"
  },
  {
    "id": "50",
    "question": "t-SNE",
    "answer": "Dimensionality Reduction Technique: good for visualizing 2D/3D high-dimensional data.",
    "links": ["43"],
    "subtopic": "Statistics"
  },
  {
    "id": "51",
    "question": "Drug Discovery",
    "answer": "Goal: give us a lead therapeutic candidate.",
    "links": ["8", "10", "52", "53", "54", "55", "58", "59", "60", "61"],
    "subtopic": "Drug Development"
  },
  {
    "id": "52",
    "question": "Biologics",
    "answer": "Larger, more complex therapeutics derived from living organisms or their cells and usually administered by injection or infusion.",
    "links": ["51", "57"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "53",
    "question": "Small Molecules",
    "answer": "Typically chemically synthesized, relatively small, and often orally bioavailable.",
    "links": ["51"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "54",
    "question": "Agonist",
    "answer": "Binds to a receptor and activates it, producing a biological response.",
    "links": ["51"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "55",
    "question": "Antagonist",
    "answer": "Binds to a receptor, but does not activate it, instead blocking the receptor and preventing other molecules from binding and activating it.",
    "links": ["51"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "56",
    "question": "Humanization",
    "answer": "The process of modifying laboratory mice so that they more closely resemble humans, primarily in their immune system or other biological systems. <ul><li>This involves introducing human genes, cells, or tissues into the mice, allowing researchers to study human-specific diseases and therapies in a more relevant preclinical model</li></ul>",
    "links": ["8"],
    "subtopic": "Drug Development"
  },
  {
    "id": "57",
    "question": "Antibodies",
    "answer": "Large, Y-shaped proteins used by the immune system to identify and neutralize antigens. <ul><li>Made up of two polypeptides (light chains) and a dimer (heavy chains)</li><li>The variable regions of the heavy and light chains (VH and VL) form the antigen-binding sites, allowing antibodies to specifically recognize and bind to antigens</li><li>The constant regions of the heavy chains (CH1, CH2, CH3, and sometimes CH4) determine the antibody's class and interact with effector cells and molecules</li></ul>",
    "links": ["52"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "58",
    "question": "Affinity (K)",
    "answer": "The strength with which a ligand binds to its receptor. A receptor with high affinity will bind to ligands even when their concentration is low.",
    "links": ["51"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "59",
    "question": "Saturation",
    "answer": "The degree to which receptors are occupied by messengers. There are only so many receptors available to bind messengers. Eventually they may all be 'in use'!",
    "links": ["51"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "60",
    "question": "Specificity (binding)",
    "answer": "The ability of a ligand to bind to one type of receptor. A messenger will only bind to a cell with the correct receptor.",
    "links": ["51"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "61",
    "question": "Competition",
    "answer": "The ability of different ligands to compete for the same type of receptor. Competitors tend to resemble the natural ligand in structure.",
    "links": ["51"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "62",
    "question": "MSE",
    "answer": "Calculates the average of the squared differences between predicted and actual values. <ul><li>It heavily penalizes larger errors due to the squaring</li><li>A lower MSE indicates better model performance</li></ul>",
    "links": ["46"],
    "subtopic": "Metrics"
  },
  {
    "id": "63",
    "question": "RMSE",
    "answer": "The square root of the MSE. <ul><li>This metric is often preferred over MSE because it is in the same units as the target variable, making it easier to interpret.</li><li>Like MSE, RMSE also penalizes larger errors</li></ul>",
    "links": ["46"],
    "subtopic": "Metrics"
  },
  {
    "id": "64",
    "question": "MAE",
    "answer": "Calculates the average of the absolute differences between predicted and actual values. <ul><li>MAE is less sensitive to outliers than MSE because it doesn't square the errors</li><li>It provides a straightforward measure of the average magnitude of errors</li></ul>",
    "links": ["46"],
    "subtopic": "Metrics"
  },
  {
    "id": "65",
    "question": "R²",
    "answer": "Represents the proportion of variance in the dependent variable that is explained by the independent variables in the model. <ul><li>It ranges from 0 to 1, with higher values indicating a better fit</li><li>A high $R^2$ suggests that the model captures a large portion of the variability in the data</li></ul>",
    "links": ["46"],
    "subtopic": "Metrics"
  },
  {
    "id": "66",
    "question": "F1",
    "answer": "Provides a balance between precision and recall. <ul><li>$F1 = \\frac{2 * \\text{precision} * \\text{recall}}{\\text{precision} + \\text{recall}}$</li></ul>",
    "links": ["47"],
    "subtopic": "Metrics"
  },
  {
    "id": "67",
    "question": "Linear Regression",
    "answer": "Predicts a line of best fit amongst continuous data.",
    "links": ["46"],
    "subtopic": "Statistics"
  },
  {
    "id": "68",
    "question": "Logistic Regression",
    "answer": "Predicts the probability of a categorical outcome (often binary).",
    "links": ["47"],
    "subtopic": "Statistics"
  },
  {
    "id": "69",
    "question": "Clinical Notes",
    "answer": "Unstructured data written by healthcare professionals to document a patient's medical or psychological assessment, diagnosis, treatment, and progress.",
    "links": ["28", "70"],
    "subtopic": "Data"
  },
  {
    "id": "70",
    "question": "CDW",
    "answer": "Clinical Data Warehouse: provides a single, unified view of patient data, enabling healthcare professionals to access and analyze information from different sources in a standardized format.",
    "links": ["27", "28", "29", "69"],
    "subtopic": "Data"
  },
    {
    "id": "71",
    "question": "Homeostasis",
    "answer": "Maintenance of critical physiologic parameters within an optimal range (for survival) via a negative feedback loop.",
    "links": ["73", "76"],
    "subtopic": "Physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": "72",
    "question": "Allostasis",
    "answer": "When the system is habituated to new normal due to repetitive changes to parameter.",
    "links": ["76"],
    "subtopic": "Physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": "73",
    "question": "Reflex Circuit",
    "answer": "A neural pathway that mediates a reflex action, which is an involuntary, automatic response to a specific stimulus. Super important in the maintenance of homeostasis: <ol><li>receptor senses parameter</li><li>afferent path</li><li>integrating center (CNS)</li><li>efferent path</li><li>effector alters parameter</li></ol>",
    "links": ["71", "74", "75"],
    "subtopic": "Physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": "74",
    "question": "Sympathetic",
    "answer": "Prepares the body for fight or flight responses. Branch of the autonomic nervous system.",
    "links": ["73"],
    "subtopic": "Physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": "75",
    "question": "Parasympathetic",
    "answer": "Promotes rest and digest functions. Branch of the autonomic nervous system.",
    "links": ["73"],
    "subtopic": "Physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": "76",
    "question": "Physiologic Reserve",
    "answer": "The body's ability to adapt to stressors and maintain normal function. We can use this concept to define disease. <ul><li>Naturally, this reserve permanently declines more rapidly with age, until 'symptoms at rest', and eventually 'death'</li><li>Acute stress (unless overwhelming) is beneficial and increases physiologic reserve because recovery is allowed</li><li>Chronic stress is ALWAYS detrimental because there is no time to repair</li></ul>",
    "links": ["71", "72", "77", "79", "80", "81", "82"],
    "subtopic": "Physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": "77",
    "question": "Mechanisms of Disease",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Physical and chemical trauma/injury</li><li>Vascular: blood delivery/perfusion</li><li>Infectious</li><li>Inflammatory/autoimmune</li><li>Genetic</li><li>Metabolic</li><li>Neoplastic (cancer)</li><li>Psychological</li><li>Idiopathic/primary/essential (mechanism unknown/multi-factorial)</li></ul>",
    "links": ["76", "78"],
    "subtopic": "Physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": "78",
    "question": "Goals of Treatment",
    "answer": "<ol><li>Prevent</li><li>Cure</li><li>Manage (slow down decline)</li><li>Palliate (alleviate symptoms)</li></ol>",
    "links": ["4", "77"],
    "subtopic": "Physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": "79",
    "question": "Acute Disease",
    "answer": "Sudden/aburpt depletion of physiologic reserve that (with recovery) will result in full recovery and strengthen physiologic reserve (sharp, temporary). <ul><li>Example: getting the flu</li></ul>",
    "links": ["76"],
    "subtopic": "Physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": "80",
    "question": "Chronic Disease",
    "answer": "The permanent, accelerated depletion of physiologic reserve (slope becomes much steeper). <ul><li>In the case of a chronic smoker, their 'slope' can reset if they quit, but it will continue at their current reserve level</li></ul>",
    "links": ["76"],
    "subtopic": "Physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": "81",
    "question": "Acute-to-chronic Disease",
    "answer": "An acute disease WITHOUT complete recovery. <ul><li>Ex. pneumonia left untreated will cause chronic respiratory problems</li></ul>",
    "links": ["76"],
    "subtopic": "Physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": "82",
    "question": "Acute-on-chronic Disease",
    "answer": "Chronic disease is hit by an acute stress without complete recovery. <ul><li>Ex. getting COVID while having weak lungs</li></ul>",
    "links": ["76"],
    "subtopic": "Physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": "83",
    "question": "Hepatic Bioavailability (Fʜ)",
    "answer": "Systemic availability of drug after hepatic first pass metabolism.<ul><li>In general, drugs with high Eʜ have low Fʜ: $F_H = 1 - E_H$</li><li>$\\text{AUC}_{po} = \\frac{F*D}{CL}$</li></ul>",
    "links": ["32", "88"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "84",
    "question": "Dosaging Steady State",
    "answer": "At steady state, rate in = rate out. In other words, infusion rate (dosage rate) = rate of elimination. <ul><li>$R_{in} = CL*C_{ss}$</li></ul>",
    "links": ["2"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "85",
    "question": "C(0)",
    "answer": "Initial Concentration <ul><li>$C(0) = \\frac{\\text{Dose}}{V_d}$</li></ul>",
    "links": ["15"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "86",
    "question": "Extraction Ratio (E)",
    "answer": "Fraction (between 0 and 1) of drug removed by organ in a single pass (assesses organ function). <ul><li>$E=\\frac{C_A-C_V}{C_A} = \\frac{C_{in}-C_{out}}{C_{in}}$</li></ul>",
    "links": ["2"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "87",
    "question": "Renal Clearance (CLʀ)",
    "answer": "Excretory clearance (kidney) where the unchanged drug is excreted into urine.<ul><li>$CL_R=\\frac{U*V}{P}$</li><li>High level: $CL_R=CL_{\\text{filt}}+CL_{\\text{secretion}}-CL_{\\text{reabsorption}}$</li><li>$CL_{\\text{filt}} = f_u * GFR$</li></ul>",
    "links": ["2"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "88",
    "question": "Hepatic Clearance (CLʜ)",
    "answer": "Metabolic clearance (liver) converting drug into metabolites, essentially removing parent compound from bloodstream.<ul><li>In a 'well-stirred' liver model: <ul><li>$E_H = \\frac{f_u*CL_I}{Q_B+f_u*CL_I}$</li><li>$CL_H = Q_B*\\frac{f_u*CL_I}{Q_B+f_u*CL_I}$</li></ul></li><li>High $E_H$ $\\rightarrow CL_H \\approx Q_B$</li><li>Low $E_H$ $\\rightarrow CL_H \\approx f_u*CL_I$</li></ul>",
    "links": ["2", "83", "89", "90", "91"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "89",
    "question": "Hepatic Blood Flow (Qʙ)",
    "answer": "The circulation of blood through the liver.<ul><li>1500 mL/min for liver</li><li>1200 mL/min for kidney</li></ul>",
    "links": ["88", "96"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "90",
    "question": "Intrinsic Clearance (CLɪ)",
    "answer": "Inherint ability of organ (usually referring to liver) to clear the drug without limitations from bloodflow/binding.<ul><li>High $CL_I \\rightarrow$ High $E_H$</li><li>Low $CL_I \\rightarrow$ Low $E_H$</li></ul>",
    "links": ["88", "97"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "91",
    "question": "Fraction Unbound (fᵤ)",
    "answer": "Fraction (between 0 and 1) of drug unbound (floating) to total drug concentration.<ul><li>$f_u = \\frac{C_u}{C} = \\frac{1}{1+K*P} = \\frac{1}{1+K(P_{tot} - DP - XP)}$</li><li>$K$ is an affinity constant</li></ul>",
    "links": ["88", "93"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "92",
    "question": "Major Plasma Binding Proteins",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Albumin</li><li>$\\alpha_1$-Acid glycoprotein</li><li>Lipoproteins</li><li>Cortisol binding globulin (transcortin)</li><li>Sex-binding globulin</li></ul>",
    "links": ["3", "93"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "93",
    "question": "Protein Binding",
    "answer": "Drugs are either floating or bound to a protein.<ul><li>$P_{\\text{total}} = P + DP + XP$</li><li>$DP$ (drug bound protein) is usually negligible because $P_{\\text{total}}$ is so much larger</li><li>$XP$ (drug bound to competiting proteins) is generally considered 0, assuming no competition</li></ul>",
    "links": ["91", "92", "95"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "94",
    "question": "Rate of Elimination",
    "answer": "$CL * C$",
    "links": ["2"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "95",
    "question": "Factors that affect Plasma Protein (fᵤ) + Tissue Binding (fᵤₜ)",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Displacing Agents (e.g. concomitant drugs)</li><li>Changes in binding protein concentration ($P_{tot}$)</li><li>Changes in drug binding affinity (K)</li><li>Changes in tissue binding protein concentration ($T_{tot}$)</li></ul>",
    "links": ["93"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "96",
    "question": "Factors that affect Qʙ",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Reduces:<ul><li>Heart Failure</li><li>Live Disease</li><li>Co-administration of beta-adrenergic blocking agents</li><li>Exercise</li></ul></li><li>Increases:<ul><li>Food</li></ul></li></ul>",
    "links": ["89"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  },
  {
    "id": "97",
    "question": "Factors that affect CLɪ",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Reduces:<ul><li>Enzyme or Influx Transporter Inhibitors</li><li>Liver Disease</li><li>Bile Transporter Inhibitors</li></ul></li><li>Increases:<ul><li>Enzyme or Influx Transporter Inducers</li></ul></li></ul>",
    "links": ["90"],
    "subtopic": "Pharmacology"
  }
]
